# Aswini Kumar Parida

Senior Software Engineer

#### **Contact**

**Address** 

Bangalore, India 560037

**Phone** 

9980316281

**E-mail** aswiniparida3087@g mail.com

### **Skills**

Java I.C

Very Good

Spring Boot, Rest services, JPA, Hibernate, Data Structures

Very Good

Microservices and Monolith,

Very Good

Maven, Git, GitHub, Junit, Mockito, Cucumber, ELK, TDD and BDD

Very Good

Agile Methodologies, TFS, Jira

Very Good

PCF, Docker, AWS KMS, S3, RDS

Good

I am working as a **Senior Software Engineer** with 8 years of Experience to the software product development. I want to pursue a challenging career in IT field with varied responsibilities which provides me opportunities to improve my knowledge and enhance my skills in technical field. I want to be part of the team that excels towards the growth of organization and meet the organization's vision.

# **Work History**

2021-05 -Current

### **Software Engineer III**

Smarsh India Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore

 Worked with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.

2020-02 -2021-05

# **Senior Software Engineer**

Harman Connected Services, Bangalore

- Worked closely with product owners, architects, developers, quality assurance team to deliver high availability solutions.
- Onboarded new microservice module Global PKI
   Provider to production along with integration with
   frontend.
- Implemented various features into IoTCloud.HMPGateway and IoTCloud.HubUpdateServices.
- Wrote highly maintainable, solid code for software system, forming core framework and earning consistent praise from subsequent developers since initial version.
- Reviewed code and worked with development teams to correct problems, run test scenarios and prepare for deployment.

2015-11 -2020-02

# **Software Engineering Professional**

BT eserv India Pvt. Ltd, Bnaglore

- Revised, modularized and updated OR-METB to modern development standards improving functionality for application.
- Developed and integrated new microservice

HTML, CSS, JQUERY, Java script

Good

MongoDB, Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, RabbitMQ, Weblogic 10.3.6

Good

- module **OR FND Aggregator** with OR-FND core with team member of size 4 and delivered to production with zero defects.
- Played role of team member of OR-MTCT rationalization to OR-METB and shutting down the systems which reduced operation costs and improved performance.
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.

2014-02 -2015-10

### **Software Engineer**

M2M Innovations LLP, Bangalore

- Wrote highly maintainable, solid code for software system, forming core framework and earning consistent praise from subsequent developers since initial version.
- Delivered unit-tested systems with required characteristics and within customer-prescribed timeframes.

# **Education**

2008-07 -2012-06

# **Bachelor of Technology: Electrical Engineering**

Institute of Technical Education And Research - Bhubaneswar, Odisha

# **Accomplishments**

- Promoted to Software Engineer Analyst from Software Engineer Associate after just 2 years of employment.
- Received spot award from PHILIPS for my ability to Take Ownership And Deliver Fast towards development, design and integration with frontend for Global PKI Provider module of IOT Services product.
- Key contributor in the design and implementation of new features for OR-FND Aggregator.